democrats.com 2015-11-13

# Privacy Policy | Democrats.com

Democrats.com LLC has served Democratic and progressive voters since 2000 and we are committed to protecting your privacy.

This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which Democrats.com LLC collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a "User") of our websites ("Sites"), including Democrats.com, Act.tv, and JobParty.us. This privacy policy applies to the Sites and all services offered by Democrats.com LLC.

Personal identification information

We may collect personal identification information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our site, register on the site, subscribe to the newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Site. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address, mailing address. Users may, however, visit our Site anonymously. We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personally identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities.

Non-personal identification information

We may collect non-personal identification information about Users whenever they interact with our Site. Non-personal identification information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users means of connection to our Site, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information.

Web browser cookies

Our Site may use "cookies" to enhance User experience. User's web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. User may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If they do so, note that some parts of the Site may not function properly.

How we use collected information

Democrats.com LLC may collect and use Users personal information for the following purposes:  
\- To personalize user experience  
We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use the services and resources provided on our Site.  
\- To improve our Site  
We may use feedback you provide to improve our products and services.  
\- To send periodic emails  
We may use the email address to send User information and updates pertaining to Democratic candidates and progressive causes. It may also be used to respond to their inquiries, questions, and/or other requests. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email or User may contact us via our Site.  
\- To deliver messages to elected officials and company executives.  
We may deliver your petition messages to elected officials and company executives. These may include personal messages you choose to add to our generic message. You may receive a reply from these officials and executives.  
\- To deliver email ads from Democratic candidates and progressive causes (partners).  
We occasionally send email advertisements from our partners, which are carefully-selected Democratic candidates and progressive causes. You may unsubscribe from our partners list at any time without affecting your newsletter subscription or community membership by following the instructions at the bottom of each partner email. If you respond to a partner ad by signing a petition or completing a form, we will forward the information you provide to our partner. For local Democratic candidates who want to represent you, we will send you their sample newsletter with an unsubscribe link if you do not want any more emails from that candidate. If you do not unsubscribe within two days, we will provide your address to the candidate, who will also include an unsubscribe link in every email they send you. We do not share or sell information with spammers.  
\- To process contributions  
We may use the information Users provide about themselves when making a contribution only to process that contribution. All such contributions will read "Democrats.com" on your credit card bill. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service. We do not store your credit card number in order to avoid fraud.  
\- To improve customer service  
Information you provide helps us respond to your customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.

How we protect your information

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Site.

Third party websites

Users may find advertising or other content on our Site that link to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the content or links that appear on these sites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our Site. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to our Site, is subject to that website's own terms and policies.

Advertising

Ads appearing on our site may be delivered to Users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile non personal identification information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy policy does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

Changes to this privacy policy

Democrats.com LLC has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.

Your acceptance of these terms

By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this policy and terms of service. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

Contacting us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please [use our webform](http://democrats.com/contact) or send a letter to:  
Democrats.com LLC  
Box 1452   
New York, NY 10276

This document was last updated on January 19, 2014
